Heat. Heat.
Hey,
hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
Hey,
hey, hey.
Hey, Heat. Heat. N.
Hey,
hey, hey.
introduction.
Hello and good morning everyone. We're
so excited to have a stacked lineup for
you here today. Please help me welcome
the first speaker, Mark Spieler from
MIT.
[applause]
>> All right. So, thank you very much. Um,
great to be here. Um, and welcome
everyone. Um, so yeah, um, I'm going to
try to be really quick. In my 15
minutes, I'll be talking about how we
use AI agents for scientific discovery.
And, um, just waiting for the slides.
These are these are not my slides, I
think. Right. Do you see? No. Okay.
How's everyone?
Great. Awesome. Good morning. And yeah,
thank you for everyone for putting this
together. Really an amazing event. Um,
am I waiting for something or I'm
waiting for my slides, right?
>> Okay, good. Just make sure. Yeah, I
don't know. It's like a test here.
They have these posterless poster shows
where you you're not supposed to have a
poster and still talk about your
research elevator pitches. So, maybe
that's it. I don't know. Well, I can
start. So um the the thing I'll be
talking about when the slides come up is
is really how we build AI systems for
open-ended discovery and I think we've
seen including actually this morning or
late last night um amazing progress in
math and of um coding of course in AI
and the thing we're working on is is
applying these tools techniques
developing algorithms and models systems
for open-ended discovery especially in
material science I'm a material
scientist oh slides up awesome great so
um so that's sort of the introduction um
we're sort of going two ways we're
looking at um building these agendic
systems for applications in engineering
and science, especially biology, but
also the other way around. I think we're
learning a lot of um design principles
and ideas from biology and building
better agendic systems like swarms. Um
and so you're going to hear me talk
about sort of these interconnections and
synergies between them. The thing that
we're really sort of fascinated with is
sort of one day to be able to come up
with a real breakthrough in discovery,
not just extending an existing paradigm
or reapplying it, actually having a
totally new language in how we describe
the world. Um, and that's really
necessary, I think, for creating AI that
ultimately makes true discoveries, you
know, changing the grammar and how we
describe the world, fundamentally
breaking what we call the world model.
And in our work, you know, we sort of
have sort of transitioned over the years
as a community from going from sort of
really simple, I think, machine learning
regression type models early on 10, 20,
30 years ago to generative AI in the
last few years to sort of sample an
existing landscape and learn from data
and then to the discovery era, which is
what we're really in right now, where
we're building models that are really
not only sort of generating new ideas
maybe, but also generating new training
data, testing them, validating them. And
I use the jazz ensemble as an analogy.
Really sort of writing the musical score
while we're solving a problem. I think
it's necessary in science because
scientific discovery means you're
proposing an idea that seems crazy and
you're validating it. You're proving it
and you have to do these sort of
verification steps. The question is how
do we get there? So obviously involves
experimentation. So we do a lot of work
in validating the the research we're
doing with AI agents. um building
systems that can you know spin off
simulations, first principle
simulations, experimentation, mining
literature, finding new evidence,
finding sort of the hidden paper in the
pile of gigantic things that have been
ignored. And what's fascinates me
particularly is this idea that these AI
agents, these systems can make other
models. So I'm a modeler. I've been
working in modeling not not since the
1950s okay but since the 2000 or so
since I had my PhD but I was sort of in
the business of writing models uh I came
from Caltech for Bill Gddard and MIT you
know writing first principles models of
systems of materials now these systems
are sort of writing their own models
compiling them running them and it's
fascinating so breaking the world is a
theme that we're talking a lot about um
again if you're creating scientific
discovery you have to break the world
and that means
things that you believe to be true um
are going to be sort of come on the
table and have to be validated and and
AI really has to change my mind about
something that I believe to be incorrect
crazy idea right and so that's really
hard in in science because we have
open-ended problems things that aren't
really verifiable very easily so here
comes the agents so agendic system
especially swarms is fascinating sort of
building not just designing not just the
model but really how the model interacts
with other systems the environment
themselves
very similar things we see in emergence
in biology. Um our cells are example for
this. We are all self assembled sort of
um ecosystem civilizations and we think
there are a lot of things to be learned.
Like I showed earlier um we do a lot of
work in building graph native reasoning
models. So what are the foundational
techniques you need to actually create
sort of executable programs? And you
know we're trying to map the world of
complexity and noisiness and messiness
with experimentation and biology and
incomplete data into uh real programs
that we can execute and compile uh and
then verify and falsify and that's a
really key component of course in
building agendic systems. Um the
beautiful thing about agendic systems is
that they can include physics in their
sort of retrieval of new data or
generation of new data. Um we have done
this and I'll just flip really quickly
through because I only have so much time
but in materials applications in
building uh new parap guide materials
for energy applications we applied this
to open-ended discovery. This is some
work we've done uh back in 2004. It's
still in peer review so the journals are
too slow for this field for sure. Um so
it's going to come out in science
advances pretty soon I hope. This is a
one of the first AI scientists actually
that's been proposed and we sort of
created the system really to do
open-ended discovery not just designing
something that we know the goal of but
actually something that we don't know
anything about. So this system sparks uh
is able to create uh discover scaling
laws and principles and if you look a
little bit under the hood a couple of
follow-up papers including the builder
breaker model that is is on archive it's
also in a journal but archive is the
source you want to look at. Um, we're
building adversarial agents that propose
ideas, build externalized world models
of any kind, uh, penalizing complexity,
maximizing coverage. So, we want a
system that explains the world in as
right as possible and have a builder
agent that creates this model and a
breaker agent that tries to break this
world model by collecting new data, new
evidence from experiment, from
literature. um ultimately creating if we
add um MDL as a gate for example for
simplicity we can get beautiful
theoretical concepts actually a search
sort of this is akin to what we call
auto research now um but now in the
open-ended space of scientific discovery
and uh the outcome of this is quite
fascinating with this in protein science
where we basically have agents that
collect new evidence from experimental
data and as the data sort of is
collected trying to break the world
model uh the data gets more complex so
more more work for the builder agent. Um
and ultimately the builder agent came up
with a beautiful theory to predict the B
factor in proteins. Simple theory
scaling in this case interpretable. So
very powerful stuff. I think the last
example that I want to talk about are
swarms and um this is a more recent
development. Fiona Wang actually is my
student. She's here. I don't know if
she's here in the room but she will be
here in the conference. She has a poster
as well building the uh decentralized
collective agents. So we don't describe
what the agents are and how they should
behave, but we let the agents discover
completely on their own. In fact, the
swarms don't just live in one lab or one
computer. They actually live all around
the world. So our vision is building
agendic systems or swarms where we have
completely centralized self- autonomous
evolving agents. Um again inspired by
biology, designing proteins,
um building systems that can discover
new protein design principles. These
spikes show you that we're really going
far away from what nature has created.
So, evolution has created a certain type
of proteins. Um, most diffusion models,
if you use standard AI, follow sort of
I'm sorry, I went too quickly. Um,
follow
Okay. Well, you remember seeing the
spike? So, the the thing in the middle
is where you see uh Yeah, it's okay. I
mean, you remember seeing it, right? So
the circle is sort of natural biology
fusion models will sample from this
distribution. Our our models the the the
swarm can f outside right and discovers
these sparks um spikes coming out and
really looking at new I think this okay
here we go. So the system is called
scienceclaw plus infinite obviously
scienceclaw um inspired by um the famous
um claw movement that came out a few
months ago and we built a bunch of
hundreds of different agents for
scientific discovery with different
skills and tools evolving skills and the
infinite is modeled after the MIT
infinite corridor. How many of you have
been to MIT? Many yes okay some. um we
have this infinite corridor where sort
of the magical place I don't know if you
guys have this here at Berkeley but
everybody goes there to the coffee shop
to the dorm and you bump into each other
and hopefully you have a great
conversation so you meet the
mathematician meets the biologists meets
the philosopher and they kind of come up
with new research ideas that's the idea
so the agents live there and solve
problems um these agents have done real
scientific work so the paper has many
examples one of them is discovering new
resonators uh meta materials so this is
a particular class of materials and
material science is very active right
now. Sort of the agents found out a
space on the very top in this example
here where no resonator had been found
yet and then figured out a way of
designing them. So this is beautiful. So
they have not only designed the
resonator but also figured out where to
go and where the most impactful research
can be done. Um the system is
decentralized completely traceable. So
once you follow the agentic interactions
hundreds of them you can see them and
the vision of course is that um that if
you are um an agent and you do things
most of the experiments you're going to
be doing are going to be wrong wrong
they're going to end up in nowhere
unlike in human papers where I might
write a paper to for nature and I'm
going to select the three experiments
that worked here every experiment ever
done by any agent is completely
traceable and stored so a future agent
can use the earlier results to built on
and I think that's the future of
scientific publishing actually. Yeah.
And this is the poster by Fiona. So
Fiona Wang I know Fiona are you here?
She's probably stuck in the other room
but so Fiona will be here and she has
posters tonight and tomorrow. So check
her out and she can talk to you a little
bit more about the system. And with that
yeah thank you so much. Um what we're
trying to do is build we call the world
building machine because we're in the
business of building materials as
engineers and scientists study biology.
And so we think that the conventional
way of course is sort of how most people
understand AI is sort of a gigantic
dictionary library. We want of course
build an AI that can write its own
library and it write its own books and
its own papers that hopefully challenge
what we believe to be true. So with
that, thank you so much and happy to
answer questions. Thank you.
[applause]
>> Two more minutes.
>> Have two more minutes. Okay. Well, we
can take questions. Yeah.
So I went I went fast I guess but yeah
any question?
Yes please.
>> Yeah so you know when you're building so
actually in this in this example the
resonator example we included
manufacturability as one of the
constraints. So in one of the recent
papers actually posted about in LinkedIn
today um we include a direct connection
to a um essentially a CAD program or
Grasshopper in our case. So we can
actually directly produce from a design
uh G-code a machine code which gives us
a really good idea first of all of
manufacturability theoretically we can
actually also send this directly to a
machine and then get data back from
there. So the the general idea of course
of authentic AI and swarms is exactly
this and the sort of more
forward-looking idea is um you know we
might have 3D printers in our lab which
we do we have protein synthesis
facilities and all that but we might not
have this other capability that we need.
So this decentralized scienceclaw
infinite system the hope of that is of
course that you can decentralize and we
can uh we can offer services. So you
might offer your services in your lab.
Maybe you have manufacturing labs. So my
agents and everybody else's agents can
talk to your agents and actually create
things and give feedback. So that we
think is the future of this whole field.
It's not just building agents that live
in one cloud, but building them to live
in multiple systems and of course
connecting in the physical hardware and
the physical world. And that is
something we're so close to doing. It's
matter of scaling and resources
essentially at this point. Yes, please.
Yeah. So I mean yeah so the question was
what's the relationship between human
researchers and the agents. Um it can be
anything. Okay. So this is an opening
question. I mean it could be that you
provide the question. You say I want to
design this peptide and the paper has
bunch of examples. Um so give me a
peptide that binds to this receptor and
it will do it. So you provide the idea.
In the resonator example it was very
open-ended. In the protein scaling
example in Sparks, it was very
open-ended. We said, "Here's a bunch of
tools. You can make your own, but you
know, figure out something interesting
and it should be something profound,
right?" And the agents tell us what to
do. So, it could be anything from really
open-ended. Now, while the agents work
and when they produce things, of course,
you become part of this ecosystem as
well. So, you can give feedback. I mean,
you look back to the um this scienceclaw
infinite system. You could be one of
these agents and you can review the
work. You can give input like you
mentioned feasibility of manufacturing.
You can give input on ethics. You could
input on other constraints and in a lot
of the work we do a lot of work with
industry on this as well. And of course
that's a key theme there. They say well
amazing three designs. However, um we
don't work with this material. Okay.
Okay, so we give the feedback to the to
the the swarm, you know, can you come up
with a material? It doesn't include this
particular chemical or this particular
product because the company doesn't have
IP for this. So, you can be part of the
system. And that's I think one of the
really amazing things about these swarms
is in fact that they're not they're not
pre-programmed. They're organized
themselves and you can be part of that
discussion as well and and give sort of
intuition questions, things that the
agent haven't thought about. Um it's not
just about optimizing something. There's
um obviously you know some ethical
considerations um economic
considerations things like this and
intuition I mean a lot of this um sort
of we have maybe um I want to say things
that we know of of what to do as
scientists as you know if you're a PI
and if or a student you have experience
you go to a conference you have
intuition what are the really exciting
topics that you could potentially apply
your technique to there are very few
papers that talk about this right
because we're not really talking about
problem selection in the papers. That's
another area again. So the human
intuition, what is it actually that you
might want to steer the swarm to do? And
that's obviously something we do all the
time. So it's a mixture of all these
things. It's fun to work with these
machines. Um and um we we love them and
hopefully they love us too. So thank you
so much. Thanks. [applause]
>> Thank you. Please now help me welcome
the next presenter, James Zoo, who's a
professor at Our Neighbors Stanford.
[applause]
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Well, thank you very much.
Really exciting to participate here. So
I I lead the AI for science lab at
Stanford's and one of the ideas that I'm
really excited about recently is
thinking about how do we um try to scale
the number of agents, the number of AI
scientist agents that actually
collaborate and work together. So I
think that's actually a really exciting
new direction of scaling. So instead of
scaling individual models but scale the
number of agents, you know, from tens of
agents to hundreds to thousands and even
millions of agents that collaborate and
see what are the new kinds of
capabilities that emerges. So I want to
give some examples of that kinds of
agentic scaling. Um so the first step we
took in this direction is we created
this virtual lab which sort of has like
initially a team of you know uh five to
10 agents that sort of emulate my
physical lab at Stanford. So in the
virtual lab we have an AI professor
agent that runs the lab and then working
with the professor we have a bunch of
different AI students you know with
different expertise ranging from
mathematics to data science to protein
design and the agents have their own
group meetings. We give them a budget so
they can actually run some experiments.
We also created for the agents a replica
of Stanford uh agent school where they
can go to the school to become better
researchers in their specific domains.
And you know after we created this
virtual lab we give the agents several
different tasks. Uh so here is in this
demo I'll show you sort of the first
project we assigned to the agents which
is actually help us to design good
binders to some of the recent SARS co
variants. Right? So in this demo right
so this is illustrates one of the agent
group meetings where the professor first
explains to the student agents what is
the goal here of the project and then
the different agents different experts
then can speak up and contribute their
ideas right in this case the imunologist
recommended designing the nanobbody um
and then the machine learning agent then
come up with some ideas how to optimize
these nanobodies
so after a series of these agent group
meetings and one-on-one discussions
between the agents they then actually
designed a pretty interesting
computational framework for optimizing
these nanobbody proteins which is
different from what people have
published before. And then by running
that framework then they came back to us
with a few of these new nanobodies that
they designed. Uh and then we was our
experimental collaborators then we
synthesized these proteins and we tested
them in the real world to show they were
actually quite effective binders in
particular they were actually better
binders than the best previous human
designed antibodies to some of the
recent co variants. So this to us was
actually quite an exciting first step to
illustrate now how a team of agents when
they collaborate can actually solve
these quite challenging open-ended
projects that we can then experimentally
validate.
So for our next step where we want to be
even more ambitious right so we said
okay so can we actually now have uh try
to emulate a much more complex
organization of like an entire farmer
company now with tens of thousands of AI
scientist agents. So we call this the
virtual biotech. So in the virtual
biotech we have a cso agent the chief
scent officer agent that runs the
virtual biotech with its own chief of
staff its own office and lawyers and so
on and then under the cso agent are
these different divisions that sort of
mirrors the standard divisions you see
in the human pharma company for example
we have a division of agents that looks
for good targets another division that
designs the molecules given those
targets a third one that designs
clinical trials and looks at safety and
so on and all of these divisions now are
operationalized by different AI
scientists agents with different roles
and specializations. For example, under
the target identification division,
right? There's one agent that's really
good at looking at all the genetics
data, another agent that's really good
at doing single cell analysis and so on.
And all of these agents then can
collaborate and tackle these much harder
problems. So here's one example of the
project we assigned to this virtual
baltech now which is help us to design
new therapeutics for a particular target
in lung cancer called CD276
which is like a transmembrane protein
that has the effect of suppressing
immune response right so there's a lot
of pharmace a lot of pharma companies
are interested in this target so we said
okay can the virtual btech actually help
us to design a new therapeutic for this
target and then this team of agents uh
involving many thousands of agents then
they actually did a lot of complic
intensive analysis looking at both
genetics data, genomics data, patients
data and so on. And by analyzing these
disease mechanisms then they came back
to us right actually a specific design
what's called a ADC or antibbody drug
conjugate where we have an antibbody
that's actually designed for this
specific CD276 protein and then
antibodies are linked to a a warhead
which like a chemotherapy payload which
then is released when the antibbody hits
that target.
So this was actually quite a a
relatively new design, right? Uh and we
haven't seen this before for CD276.
And then what's really exciting was that
uh several months later uh so Mercy sort
of then independently actually uh
designed the same antibbody drug
conjugate for CD276 and then they
experimentally tested this in human
populations to show that it's actually
quite effective which received FDA
breakthrough designation. So this to us
was also really exciting as a way to
sort of independently see how the
designs from a virtual biotech can then
be independently cooperated by human
studies. You know in this case from Merc
in order to design and make these all
these know thousands of agents work
effectively in science. We found that's
actually really useful to actually
create a new layer of infrastructures
and environments for these scientist
agents. So for example a lot of existing
scientific databases right including
databases that contains all of these
biological proteins they're more
designed mostly designed to be consumed
by humans or so by consumed by you know
pre preai uh kind of algorithms. So
often these databases and APIs are too
brittle and too limited to be used by
agents efficiently. So what we did was
actually then take all these existing
databases right that contains millions
of proteins and molecules and gene
expressions and then convert all of that
into agent native virtual file systems
which makes it much easier for AI
scientist agents and to be able to inst
syn synthesize and then uh aggregate
information across all these different
data sources.
Uh and here's just a comparison that
shows so we call this paper clip and
then here's a comparison that shows that
if you actually use this kind of agent
native file virtual file systems to
represent all of the scientific data
sets and knowledge right so you actually
get much better accuracy compared to
let's say if you use clot science for
the latest clot models right but it's
also a word of magnitude faster and
cheaper than if you give the same
language models access to these
databases through the traditional MCPS
or APIs
So we've actually uh gone through this
process of essentially using this
virtual file systems now to identify all
of scientific knowledge which includes
all of the papers that people have
published full text papers on the
archive and other places and all these
different databases that's all actually
under paperclip. It's all free actually.
So you can then with one line of code
then give all of that knowledge to your
agents in this virtual file system that
enables the agents to be actually much
more effective in leveraging this. So
this is something that we've one of the
infrastructures that we built that
enables the virtual baltech to be much
more effective.
Um so the last part I want to mention is
now you know we talked about how we can
go from a virtual lab with tens of
agents to a virtual baltech now with
tens of thousands of agents but what
happens can we scale that even further
where we have millions of scientist
agents that collaborate.
So I think this is sort of a really
exciting opportunity for us to really
reimagine what all of human knowledge
would look like when we try to identify
them. Right? So the past hundreds of
years the way that humans represent
knowledge is in really in the form of
these very passive artifacts uh that we
call static papers. Right? So you know
people will write this paper but often
it's very difficult for readers or for
collaborators to figure out how to adapt
the knowledge from that paper just by
reading the static words. So our idea is
that why don't we turn all of those
static artifacts of knowledge from
papers into dynamic and interactive
virtual authors that we call paper
agents right so each paper agent then
it's like a virtual author that uh
represents all the knowledge from that
paper so in this case right so here I
can just ask the paper agent right can
you apply help me to apply the method
from that paper to my own data sets of
my own problem and the paper agent then
would do that automatically and generate
reproducible workflows post and come
back to me with the end discoveries and
results.
So the goal of this is that by
identifying all of these passive
knowledge into dynamic virtual authors
then this makes knowledge much easier to
disseminate also easier to uh form
collaborations.
So under the hood right we created
actually this paperto aent automated
workflow that converts static knowledge
into dynamic agents. So briefly what
happens is that we have a bunch of
different worker agents that goes into
the original paper and any associated
code and data and these virtual agents
these uh worker agents basically creates
a virtual environment try to replicate
the original research process for
example by replicating the results from
that paper in the process of doing that
then we actually create this paper agent
a paper MCP which then can be turned
into a paper agent.
So one of the applications of this is
that now we can actually ask these
knowledge agents to help to make sure
the knowledge itself is actually
reproducible. Right? So in this case the
paper agent is able to generate all the
intermediate figures and results that ma
matches the original publication. So in
this case the paper was reproducible but
in many other cases you also found that
the paper agent actually identified key
mistakes and mis and limitations in the
original publications.
So the last part the thing I'll mention
is that I think maybe the most exciting
application of all these paper agents is
that I think this enables a new form of
collaborations between different agents
right so we are now in the process of
justifying every paper that people have
ever published so millions that will
create actually millions of paper agents
and now these agents can are starting to
talk to each other to generate new
collaborations so this is a real example
of this where Google deep mind published
a paper called alpha genome a few months
ago so it's paper to agent that
identified into an agent that knows how
to use that tool. And then a separate
research group published a genetic data
set for mutations linked to GW was for
risk for ADHD that was also turned into
a paper agent that knows how to use that
data set. In this case, those two agents
actually started to talk to each other,
decided they could collaborate, and then
automatically discover a new mutation
that increases the risk for uh for ADHD,
which is not known before. So we're
starting to see many more of these
examples of these paper agents starting
to collaborate. So I'll wrap up here. So
I hope to show these few examples to
illustrate why we're really excited
about this new axis of capabilities that
that emerges when we are scaling up the
number of scientist agents that starts
to collaborate and work with each other
and also work with human researchers.
Thank you very much.
[applause]
>> Thank you, professor. All righty. Next
up, we have Eric Ho, who is the CEO and
co-founder at Goodfire. Please all help
me welcome Eric Ho.
[applause]
>> Hey everyone.
Just waiting for slides.
Maybe I'll just quickly introduce
myself. I'm Eric. I'm co-founder CEO of
Goodfire. Uh we're the leading AI
interpretability research company. So we
spend all day thinking about, you know,
what's going on inside the mind of of an
AI model. And uh today I'm going to talk
to you about uh you know kind of one
idea which is that we can reverse
engineer superhuman AI models to
understand their computations to advance
science and teach us about the world. Uh
and there will soon hopefully be slides
about this.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah, can automatically
load up slides.
Well, in the meantime, I could talk a
little bit about what we're up to. Uh,
so GoodFire, uh, AI interpretability
research company. Uh, we spend all of
our days thinking about what's actually
going on inside the mind of AI models.
So really looking inside of an AI model,
looking at their neurons, their
parameters, their computations with the
hope of understanding what they're
doing. The reason why we care so much
about understanding what we're doing is
that well, first of all, like we really
should understand the most consequential
technology of all time. We should really
understand these these systems that
we're putting everywhere in the world.
Um but also we hope to build towards a
future of what we call intentional
design which is a future where we can
actually understand and edit and debug
these systems much more like written
software not just kind of training them
by trial and error as we as we do today.
And so that's like kind of our our whole
agenda. We're headquartered in SF um and
uh have been around for for a couple
years kind of looking into these these
problems. Uh and I think one of the most
interesting things about this is that uh
there are already you know superhuman AI
models that are out there in the world
today like you know for narrow game
playing scenarios like Alpha Zero and
Alph Go uh those are already superhuman
at their tasks. uh and there are also
you know superhuman scientific models
that uh we hope to kind of reverse
engineer uh understand and then in that
way you know kind of push forward
science um and uh I think that's one of
the most you know promising directions
of of our time [snorts]
>> yeah you can ask questions sure yeah
kill time.
[laughter]
>> Oh yes, questions.
>> Yeah. So the question was uh about
responsible AI steering and aligning AI
models. Uh this is a really big part of
our original motivation for founding the
company. uh it feels difficult for me to
to see a future where we can really
align AI models and get the systems that
we want uh without deep understanding.
And so a big part of our direction is
yeah intentional design in other words
like actually steering and guiding
training such that we can pick the
updates to models that we actually want
and then remove the updates that we
don't want. So for example we have uh
techniques available. Um one of these
techniques is called reinforcement
learning with feature rewards. A feature
is kind of an internal computation of a
model that we've extracted and we
understand what it does. And so features
can be anything from like you know
unsafe behavior hacking hugging face
might be a feature. Uh and if we can
extract that and we can say hey we don't
want that in the model. uh we can
actually steer and use that feature to
steer and guide the training of a model.
Uh so big part of our our direction and
uh we've essentially developed these
techniques that can take arbitrary
features, train on them and steer and
guide the the training of models.
Yes.
Uh I wouldn't Oh, so the question is uh
sounds like we're an AI governance uh
company. Are we? Um so not quite. Uh we
are uh bu de developing a product um
it's called silico it's oh slides
wonderful um but yeah we're we're
developing a product called silicico you
can think of it kind of like a AI
neuroscientist that goes in understands
designs and debugs models so uh you can
think of us as a a different way to
train AI models and we're kind of both
doing the the science in order to
uncover a different way to train models
as well as building the platform that
brings that to to you. Okay, great. We
have slides. I did not remember what
slides I had, so this is very helpful.
Uh, okay. So, we think we can unlock a
future of scientific abundance. Uh, and
one of the best possible ways to do that
is by truly understanding superhuman AI
models. Uh the hard problem about even
if you take a superhuman AI model as a
given, when you look inside of this
model, all you're going to see are a
bunch of random looking numbers and
computations that you can't make our
heads or or tails of as a human. These
models are getting really big like
trillion parameter models. Uh no human
can actually understand a bunch of you
know trillion numbers that are hidden
inside their their weights and
parameters.
And when you also ask a model to explain
its own computations,
they are often unfaithful. So the actual
tokens that the model emits uh often are
not actually faithful to their
computation. There are clashes between
those. So you can't necessarily trust a
model to explain exactly what's what's
on its mind and how it's forming its
computation. And so this is really the
quest in the problem of
interpretability. It's how do you take
this jumbled mess of numbers and
parameters and turn that into a human
understandable explanation such that we
can understand something about about
this model
and interpretability really is the
bridge to reverse engineering the
computations of these models to teach us
about the world. So I'll give you a
problem setup here. Who's familiar with
move 37 alpho big moment? Okay. So, uh,
Alph Go was this GoPlaying AI that
Google created. Uh, and there's this big
moment where Alph Go was competing
against Lee Sadull, who was the best Go
player in the world at the time in this,
you know, best of, uh, I believe it was
like seven series. And in game two, uh,
Alph Go made a very, very surprising
move, move 37 that everyone originally
thought was a total mistake. Uh it turns
out that this was a really consequential
move that kind of shifted the the
dynamic of the game and uh Alph Go beat
Lisa doll handily. And so the question
is what was going on there? What was
happening inside of AlphaGo's
representations that caused it to have
uh to create this move? And it didn't do
this by random. there's some rich
representation space of Alph Go that
made it actually be able to uh some
richer understanding of the game than
any human had that made it be able to
produce this move of such a high high
caliber and so the setup here is we as
humans have a representation space let's
call it H
alpho machines AI have some
representation space let's call it M
what we're really interested in is this
intersection of M and H where uh We may
be able to learn new things about the
world from AI by actually understanding
their computation, but we have the
capacity to understand what is actually
going on. And this may sound like
science fiction, but my co-founder Tom,
he's our chief scientist at Goodfire,
uh, actually already did this with Alpha
Zero, the best, you know, better than
any chess player alive. So, they were
able to show in a couple papers at at
GDM. He was actually collaborating
directly with Demis on this. Uh that
reverse engineering alpha zero is
possible and that we could actually
reverse engineering in narrow positions
uh computation that actually taught
human chess grand masters how to play
chess more effectively.
And so this is a large part of our
mission which is to understand really
kind of the scientific foundations of AI
models such that we can extract
scientific knowledge from these models
and then teach them to to humans so that
you know we don't get left in the dust.
Um, one of the ways that we actually do
this, like how you actually
operationalize this is by training this
type of AI neuroscientist that goes in
across, you know, trillion parameter
models, billion parameter models to
actually reverse reverse engineer their
computations and understand kind of what
looks like gibberish as neuron to a
human and actually translate that into a
human interpretable concept. You can do
things with arbitrary concepts inside
language models and image models. You
can extract like the concept of the
Golden Gate Bridge or sick of fancy
agreeing with the user. But the point of
today is to talk about much more
interesting behaviors like uh novel
science in biology.
To start, it's really important to be
able to understand what the structure is
act is of a model. And so we've released
recent research um talking about this
concept of neural geometry.
AI models think in complex shapes. If
you take a look at that manifold,
usually it spins and it's like some type
of curved geometry uh rather than kind
of just words or directions or
individual numbers. And so we're really
interested in this idea of you know what
is the structure contained inside these
models because the structure uh may
contain insights about our natural world
that we would not have gotten to
ourselves. And I'll walk through a
couple examples of the things that we've
already done.
We are working with a company called
Prima.
They train an epigenetics foundation
model called Pletes which they use in
order to predict uh Alzheimer's. Um and
uh it is actually state-of-the-art at
all Alzheimer's detection from self-free
DNA. But they had no idea how this model
actually worked. And so what we were
able to do is use our AI neuroscientist
to go in reverse engineer that model's
computations and actually uncovered that
uh the model was mostly using this
fragmenttoic biioarker
uh to predict Alzheimer's. This was a
surprising result that wasn't contained
in the literature at the time. This was
published in the New York Times a few
months ago. uh and it it generalized
when tested on a uh independent cohort.
And how it actually represented this
fragmenttoic signal is in this kind of
half donut manifold shape um that
represented fragment length. And so we
needed to both develop the tools in
order to extract manifold computations
from models as well as understand
exactly what it was doing which was
representing fragment length.
Example number two is uh research that
we've done with Mayo Clinic on uh
understanding genetic variants and and
mutations.
So we primarily focused on SNIPS here.
Um so single nucleotide polymorphisms
uh on single genetic variants. Uh we
wanted to understand kind of you know
what variants actually caused disease uh
which ones are pathogenic. And we were
able to use the embeddings of a DNA
transformer, a DNA foundation model in
order to get state-of-the-art results on
um predicting which variants actually
cause disease. And you kind of have this
uh really rich, you know, structure that
we were able to kind of map the model
into uh in order to um get the state of
the art accuracy.
So that's kind of the high level of all
this. uh we're just at the beginning of
kind of this this quest of taking you
know superhuman scientific models
understanding what they've learned
validating them you can think of this as
a hypothesis generation loop for novel
insights and discovery and then uh I
think this is just one of the most
promising ways that we have to advance
science especially since you know AI
capabilities are going up and to the
right
and so uh yeah we've developed this
system it's called silico uh it'll
actually be in public access next week.
So keep an eye out for that. But you'll
be able to actually apply these
techniques to any model that you're
you're training, biology, materials,
physics, all these scientific models. Um
we uh have essentially a system that um
unleashes our AI neuroscientists to go
and kind of reverse engineer their
computation.
Okay, that's all I got. Thanks everyone.
[applause]
Thank you so much, Eric. I love your
improvisation skills. That was really
nice. All right. Next up, we have
Mingu Kang, who will be presenting um
for Andrew Shawn, who couldn't make it
today, who's a partner in EA. Andrew um
Mingu Kang is at UC Berkeley. So, please
welcome him.
[applause]
Oh, am I also going through that?
[laughter]
Please, please.
I wonder if AI could solve these kind of
problems. I'm going to talk about some
quantum science and maybe [snorts]
quantum science could solve this.
We're speaking about going to Mars and
we still have these problems. I think
it's
Sure.
uh uh we're trying to build uh an
agentic system that can orchestrate any
frontier research in science and we're
starting from quantum science and you'll
see it from the slides hopefully it will
appear but really I'm from quantum doing
research in quantum and it's really
multi-disiplinary there's a lot of
different layers we have to link there's
like physics of course and chemistry and
math and all these things of course very
hardcore engineering and material
and and ideally one person would know
all of the this from the stack and
connect these different ideas so that
you can really co-design everything from
end to end. Uh and that would be the
really optimal way to build a quantum
computer. We're really out of resources.
So um doing such thing is really would
be really useful and I'm sure that is
the case for any uh frontier research.
So but the interfacing is the real
problem here.
um because like a researcher will be an
expert in one layer but another
researcher will be an expert in another
layer and it'll be really hard to just
do the handoffs. So with AI I really see
the promise of um an AI understanding
all of those context and uh facilitating
the handoffs.
So that's what I'm really excited about
and I'm not excited about the slides not
coming out but
yeah so
yeah I guess I'll just first few slides
are introductory so maybe I can just go
on. So the title of the talk is solving
quantum science problems with smart a
self-evolving multi- aent research tree
and um
yeah uh since we're in the AI for
science session there are three pillars
of scientific discovery one is
intelligence one needs to synthesize
knowledge and go through the sequence of
planning working and verifying as you
might all be familiar with and the
second pillar is computation. Now I'm in
the quantum computing business. So
computation is really important. Uh one
needs to uh simulate large system and
optimize over a vast solution space. And
finally the third pillar will be
validation that will be doing actual
experiments and testing predictions
against reality the real world. So I'm
envisioning an Asian system that can
orchestrate the loop over these all
three pillars and that will really lead
us to transformative scientific
discoveries.
I hope the slide appear at this point
but [laughter] still did not. Yeah. And
yeah, so
and we're starting with quantum science
and that's because we think of it as the
strategic Everest.
Um
One minute. Okay,
this is not my slide unfortunately.
Maybe the technology has evolved too
much.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uh I guess I could take one
question.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yes, please.
>> Uh, as you'll see, we're starting with
neutral atoms because we're solving a
very interesting problem there. It's
about moving atoms around. You'll see
later. Hopefully, a video which will be
really challenging for this presentation
system. But yeah, we're starting from
neutral atoms and then but really we're
we're not even limiting ourselves to
quantum science. We're certainly not
limiting ourselves to a particular
platform. Okay, perfect.
Okay. Solving chronoscience problems
with smart self-evolving multi- aent
research tree. My name is Mingu Kong and
this is a joint work with Daniel Lee and
Andrew Sha.
All right, that's what I was talking
about three pillars of scientific
discovery. First is intelligence, second
is computation and third is validation
doing actual actual experiments. So an
agentic system that can go over this
loop would lead us to transformative
scientific discoveries
and uh our first target domain for
scientific discoveries is quantum
science which is our strategic effort.
Why start with quantum? One reason is
that quantum science is very challenging
and multi-disiplinary.
Quantum science is a mix of frontier
research in math, physics, computer
science, engineering, material science
and so on. Another reason is that
quantum science demands extreme rigor.
Unless every single piece is correct,
the quantum experiments simply would not
work.
Another reason is that the quality delta
in quantum research is massive. So the
high quality research is very rare and
the experts are very concerned about AI
slop.
So once we climb the strategic Everest
then we believe that the agentic system
will be capable of leading scientific
discoveries in any domain.
Here's a single slide review of um
quantum computing which is at the center
of quantum science. First, quantum logic
works with cubits, not bits. A bit is a
zero or one just like a coin flip, but a
cubit can be in a superp position of
zero and one states which can be at any
point on a sphere.
Second, quantum physics gives us access
to cubits. For example, you can take two
of the stable electronic energy levels
of an atom to form a cubit.
And finally, quantum hardware platform
gives us full control of the quantum
physics to compute with cubits. What you
see here is an array of atoms that you
can control with lasers.
So, um building a quantum computer like
this is obviously very challenging
experiment and that involves a lot of
deep theories which makes this the
strategic Everest for uh scientific
discovery agents.
And now let's move on to the agentic
system that we're building. We strongly
believe that transformative scientific
discoveries will come from human AI
collaboration. And this leads us to
three key design principles. The first
design principle is that the workflow
tree keeps getting updated as the agents
explore.
And the second design principle is that
the agentic system is structured but
also flexible.
And another another design principle is
that the agents are autonomous but also
allow humans to intervene at any time.
And that means we need a completely
different agent system than loop
engineering which is widely used for
tasks that are much simpler than
scientific discovery.
That leads us to smart the self-evolving
multi- aent research tree. The main
feature is that we have a tree
consisting of nodes where each node is
consisting of planner, worker and
verifier agents. Then the verifier agent
outputs are fed into the tree planner
agent which designs the workflow tree of
the next set.
And here are some example trees. Each
node can be either a goal or a task. And
at the next step, the task can be split,
merged, selected, or added.
And here's an example user interface. In
research, unpredictable things always
happen, just like slides not appearing
or the laptop crashing. So, it's really
important to have the flexibility to
allow human intervention.
Here's
another user interface example where the
human researcher is probing the outputs
that the agents produced. And here the
key features are managing the context,
uh using the models, choosing the
models, and tracking the cost.
Okay, now let's move on to the benchmark
results.
While there are many different agentic
systems for scientific discovery, smart
has advantages in that it is both
steerable and adaptive. And because we
and that's because we designed it to be
structured and flex uh structured and
flexible at the same time.
We compared the performance of our alpha
prototype of smart against Frontier
models and systems on a scientific
reasoning benchmark called Frontier
Science made by OpenAI.
And as you can see here, our prototype
is achieving the highest accuracy with
the cost that is only one/5if the cost
of the second best system which is codex
5.5.
And the low cost is achieved by using
GLM 5.1 as the underlying model and the
um high accuracy is achieved by
orchestrating the agents.
We can plot the same thing on a 2D chart
where y-axis is the accuracy and x-axis
is the cost. And it's very clear that
smart defines the pared frontier with
high accuracy and low cost. And this is
just our prototype. So I'm sure we can
boost the performance by further
optimization.
Okay. Now let's move on to how we can
use smarts to solve real world problems
in quantum science which is speeding up
neutral atom quantum computers.
Quantum computing is all about doing
computation faster. So we want to reduce
the wall clock time. In this case, we
want to speed up performing the quantum
circuits with neutral atoms. So what you
see on the left is a quantum circuit.
The horizontal lines are the cubits and
we apply these things called quantum
gates. The blue ones are called
entangling gates and they are performed
by putting two cubit atoms close
together
close together uh in the entanglement
zone.
So to perform a quantum circuit in the
zoned architecture neutral atom quantum
computer you first need to allocate
these cubit atoms in the slots of the
storage zone and then you shuttle the
atoms in and out of this entanglement
zone so that you can perform the
entangling gates.
But there's a caveat. We can't just
arbitrarily move the atoms around. As
we're using laser beams to move around
the atoms there are certain constraints
that need to be satisfied. For example,
what you see on the top left corner is
that uh the rows and columns that define
a block of atoms cannot cross the rows
and columns of the other block.
So this leads us to a very interesting
uh problem.
Given the quantum circuit and the zoned
architecture, what is the optimal
allocation and routing of the cubid
atoms such that the rearrangement time
can be minimized while satisfying the
atom movement constraints?
It's a very challenging problem that
where the solution space is very vast
and it's also really important for
neutrum quantum computers and that's why
we choose this as the first problem to
discover better solutions with our
agentic system smart
and here are the results. Uh here lower
numbers are better because that means it
takes less time to perform the circuit.
And across these four uh benchmark
quantum circuits, smart solutions
achieve from 83% to 25% lower
rearrangement time compared to the
state-of-the-art.
And now let's look at the ablation
studies to understand how the agents
find better solutions. Here multiple
agents explore different strategies as
listed below the chart. And here really
the takeaway is that different circuits
are improved by different combinations
of strategies.
For example,
for example on the left for the graph
state circuit uh the rearrangement time
is reduced by 83% by solely using the
structure of the circuit. While on the
right for the QPE exact circuit the 25%
reduction comes from a combination of
parameter tuning and a star redesign.
And here using the structure does not
help at all. So really this
complimentarity of different strategies
is what makes the multi- aent framework
so powerful.
And here's how smart is used for this
problem. Uh first agents explore
different strategies and then the tasks
are split, merged and so on until they
find the better solution.
Now here is a simulated video of um
rearranging the atoms. Please focus on
the right panel as it finishes very
fast.
Oh, it works.
So, as you can see here, the smart
solution clearly exploits some kind of
structure while the baseline
state-of-the-art fails to do so. So, it
takes much longer time.
With that, I'll just put the conclusion
slide here. But I I just want to point
out that there are other tremendously
interesting and challenging problems in
quantum science such as error correction
that we can uh solve with smart and that
would be the pl uh the proving ground
for building agents that lead us to
transformative scientific discoveries in
various frontier domains. Thank you for
listening.
Thank you so much and thank you for
bearing with us as we deal with the
technical issues, but we think we've got
it figured it out. So, next up we've got
Mangdi Wang. Please help me welcome
Mangdi Wang.
And Mangdi is a professor at Princeton.
>> Thank you.
>> Uh hello everyone. It's uh it's my
pleasure to be here. So we just heard
about like so many ad so much advances
in like uh AI agents in the digital
space. So if we really think about uh
scientific research, so I think the
previous speakers already say that so
there are uh several important stages
like hypothesize which is like how to
make models to think to uh reason and to
dig deeply and then computation which is
to simulate to use surrogate models to
simulate and try to find the the best uh
candidates. Okay. Uh but the last step
is validation is verification. Okay. So
it turns out that verification has
become the major bottleneck for scaling
any AI models. That is why there are so
many AI companies and AI startups that
are actively building new trace data who
are actively building I would say new RL
environments. Okay. So I think AI will
scale much faster if there's a way to
scale environments and verification. But
however this is damn hard in science.
Okay. So let me ask you a question. So
let's pick a random paper on nature. Say
it's uh a chemistry paper or a biology
paper. So do you know what's the
percentage
of nature papers that can be
reproducible?
Someone want to guess
>> 5%.
[gasps]
>> 30. Okay. So you must have seen this.
Okay.
uh actually so there was a survey run by
like uh researchers and nature that it
turns out that 70% of biomedical
research papers are not reproducible
by others
and 50% are not even reproducible by the
same authors
and this is true across domains
chemistry biology physics uh uh earth
environments okay and uh the problem is
simply because verification is hard.
Okay, the problem is because um when we
when someone actually run an experiment
in at a bench or in a clean rooms. Okay,
so there's isn't way to backtrack as how
we backtrack in a agent workflow. There
are not checkpoints.
I mean in training models we have
checkpoints but there's no checkpoints
in physical experimentation. Okay. uh
and there isn't any log there's any
there isn't any way to debug to look at
the log and debug and to improve the
harnessing. Okay, so this is why science
is so damn hard.
Okay, so uh my colleague wrote a blog uh
a few months ago and uh the conclusion
is like with AI science is not faster.
Science is actually getting slow slower.
So the reason is I mean I think in the
most recent Europe submission there are
40,000 submissions there are just too
many papers but validation and
verification actually provides new
knowledge and new information that ver
verification is not sped up so we have
more papers more agents meaning that we
have even worse signal to noise ratios
it's actually harder to get useful
information with so many AI generated
content
Okay, going back to the verification
problem.
We can have all the fancy models telling
us how to do telling us millions of
novel hypothesis, but the bottleneck is
going to be in the lab. And our poor
scientists colleagues, they devote their
careers years of work in the physical
laboratories. But it's very hard to
really speed up that process. And even
though scientists try their best, this
entire workflow workflow is still very
errorprone. Okay, that's what we need.
Okay, so [snorts] now if we think about
this, the big question is how do we turn
every scientific lab into a verifiable
environment?
So on one side AI advancing so quickly,
we have all the fancy models. We have
multiple AI co-cientists from every
major frontier AI labs and every
startup.
However, on the other end
for verification,
so scientists really work hard and
devote their career to working at the
bench in clean rooms. They have to spend
months or even months months to years to
validate a scientific hypothesis. So
we're missing something critical here
and this is where we want to build.
Okay. So we came up with a simple gadget
which we call it lab OS. It's an AI XR
agent. It's a multimodel reasoning AI
that hides behind smart glasses.
So Simmeran uh she is a undergrad intern
who is visiting from India and with the
help of lab OS she can perform advanced
genome engineering experiment pretty
much on day one. So we provide a
solution so that every single action
every single state changes in a
scientific lab becomes observable by AI
and in the same time one can build
multi-ter streaming systems. So AI can
assist human researchers in real time to
catch errors to digitalize physical
workflows to troubleshoot and to provide
guidance and hints when something
doesn't work.
Okay, this is another example that we're
building.
Okay, it's not an animation. So, this is
uh built together with my colleagues at
uh Princeton Quantum Institute. So, we
have been building this end to end mini
robotic lab for automating the nanop
fabrication of one atom thin layer
graphing devices. And again, it's a
multimodal agent that runs self auto
research inside the computer. But actual
work, the measurements, the fabrication,
the tape outs and all the microscopic
imaging were done by the robot. And by
building this system, we're actually
automating work that used to take
physics purity students three months.
And now we can get this done in one
week. And my colleague is actually
releasing this system into an API. So
anyone can submit a job to reproduce the
experiment and to test new hypothesis in
that lab and we want to enable this at
scale.
>> Sorry
uh we are going to have to cut for time.
Sorry professor
>> slide lastide. Okay. Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Uh so finally we are uh piloting
the lab OS system which is a system that
enables human researchers to work side
by side with robots. Again, every single
physical workflow will be digitalized
and every single trace will be collected
and reasoned by the AI and this is a
system that can generalize across
scientific domains from biology labs,
chemistry labs to clean rooms and nano
facilities. So that's the end of my
talk. Oh, now it works.
Thank you so much. [applause]
Thank you very much.
>> Thank you, Professor Wang. Next up,
please help me welcome Rose Yu. Rose is
a professor at UC San Diego and is the
CEO and co-founder of Just Flow. Rose,
please come to the stage.
[applause]
All right. Um, while we're waiting for
the slides, good morning everyone. Thank
you for the organizers. It's a amazing
amazing event. So, I'm a professor at UC
San Diego. I direct the spatial temporal
machineing lab. So we build machine
learning algorithms for the physical
world.
Um today I wanted to talk a little bit
about a question that has been buggling
us for the past few years. How can we
build a AI co-scientist that actually
help you with research not as chatbot
but as partners that can reason in a
physical universe and then lead to
open-ended discoveries.
So to answer that question, we have been
thinking about what are the unique
challenges of AI for science when it
come to the physical universe. As we
know in the physical world we have the
laws of physics, the symmetries, the
conservation laws and how can we build
this type of guardrails into the current
agentic system
and a lot of times physical sciences use
very expensive simulations though the
simulations where whether it's
simulating how the climate going to
change in 50 years or simulating how a
disease is going to spread in the large
community of billions of people or we're
simulating how atoms are interacting
with each other in materials in
biological systems and the simulations
are built from first principle
mathematical models but these
simulations oftent time takes long time
weeks if not days to run and get the
feedback when we want to build the
gentic system and we want to use these
type of simulation as world models to
verify our agents. How can we interact
with this type of environment?
And a lot of times when we think about
useful event, interesting events, these
events are rare and they carry huge
amount of uncertainty. So how can we
calibrate this kind of uncertainty so
that when the agent says I'm 100% sure
that tomorrow is going to rain then we
know it's actually 100% correct.
So all these challenges are breaking the
common assumptions that we have for a
gentic system. How can we build agents
that adaptively interwin between
internal reasoning and these expensive
simulations that could run for days? Um,
how can we bake in the laws of physics
in the reasoning engine of these agents?
And how can we properly calibrate the
uncertainty?
Next slide.
So to do that, we need agents that can
trade off between do adaptive tool use
that can integrate formal reasoning
tools into the verifiable environment
and this type of recipe that we built
over the years is called physicsguided
AI. So I wrote a paper at PNAS National
Science of Academy to describe what we
think is the right approach, right
recipe to build AI agents by grounding
them with laws of physics.
So we have differential equations that
are the building blocks of simulations.
We have symmetries that are governing
principles of the physical universe. How
can we ground our agents with this lot
of physics and then loop them into the
agentic open-ended reasoning loop?
And this recipe works. Um, I will say
we're very excited about the agentic
future of physical science and then we
are applying it to many different areas.
For example, when we build AI scientists
for climate science to understand the
impact of climate change, we can run
simulations really quickly using
adaptive reasoning loop so that agent
can trade off between very fast
retrieval from memory and very expense
expensive climate model projections and
that lead to two times more accurate
question answer results for climate
related reasoning tasks. We built
verifiers that can leverage formal
methods in ling and Isabel to ground
these reasoning engines to solve
mathematical theorems. We were number
one on putnam bench which is one of the
hardest formal math theorem proving
benchmarks and we were able to beat the
proprietary solutions by bidance from
50% to 70% problem solving. uh we were
able to design drugs that are evaluated
by molecular dynamic simulators that
have 18 to 35% more better favorable
binding energies. Just as a concrete
example, we have this built this agent
called deferris and this is the first
agentic weather scientist that can read
huge amount of weather data highly
numerical generate and run code in a
parallel code execution environment.
orchestrate a wide range of tools from
climate simulator to weather forecaster
and then write a report to understand
the impact of extreme events such as
wildfire and earthquakes. And this type
of analysis will typically take weather
scientists a couple of weeks to do. Now
using agents who can do that in couple
of hours.
Um and recently you know we've done a
lot of research to generate physics
grounded agents for the lab for the
physical science and we want to take
that to the real world. So we wanted
we've launched this startup that I'm the
CEO of to take the site of a same type
of recipe from the lab to the physical
world where we wanted to deploy agents
that can automatically deter
forecasting simulation what if scenarios
and actionable insights to support
supply chain and operation which is the
critical infrastructure for the physical
economy. And in this agent
we can ask a natural doesn't work. Can
you play this? Thank you.
In this Can you play this?
In this agent, you can ask a natural
language question. If there's a typhoon
that hits South, imagine you're a chip
manufacturer and you want to understand
if there's a typhoon that hit Southeast
Asia, how should we understand the
impact on the shipping lengths and the
lead time and then optimize and mitigate
the potential disruptions on your
business and then our agent can do
adaptive research to find all the
impacted lines and then estimate the
disruptions on lead time arrival and
come up with a mitigation. plan in a
couple hours. Um, so with that, I want
to thank all the funding agencies for
supporting this work. We're just
launching this company, so if you're
interested, please come talk to us. And
we're very excited to show the world
what we can build. Thanks.
>> Thank you, professor.
>> Thank you, Professor Yu.
Next up, please help me welcome Jonathan
Welch. He is the head of AI at Albert
Invent.
>> I may not even wait for the slides just
given the way things are going. So, um,
thank you everybody. Really appreciate
you listening to me today. Um, I'm
Jonathan Welch. I lead AI at Albert. Uh,
Albert is an AI native operating system
that was built to be a collaborative
surface where AI agents and chemists can
work together to accelerate discovery
and uh, bring new materials to market
faster. We are an R&D platform for some
of the largest chemical companies in the
world. Uh, and when it comes to
deploying AI at enterprise scale, we've
learned that how skeptical bench
chemists can actually be. um because
they are inventing things that um
sorry they expect a lot of it and they
don't forgive even simple mistakes much
less costly complex ones very easily. Um
but today I want to share with you some
of the lessons that we've learned and
what we think that actually means for
developing agentic discovery tools for
industrial chemistry um and some things
to consider if you're building for this
domain. So industrial chemistry for us
this is the chemistry that makes up the
room around us. This is the paints and
coatings on the walls. Uh the glass
adhesive, I'm sorry, the the adhesives
on uh your phones, the coatings on your
your glasses. Um the personal care
objects are products you may have used
this morning. And these are all
formulated products. Uh formulation
science is actually the largest domain
in industrial chemistry. More than half
of a $200 billion annual R&D spend goes
towards formulated products like these.
And [snorts] it's in this domain that
actually for agentic co-scientists it is
the least accessible because most of the
knowledge today that determines success
lives in tacid unpublished proprietary
form and it is seldom if ever surfaced
to the actual public sphere. Now in this
domain today Albert's co-scientists
actually help our partners invent
products that over a billion people
depend upon every day. This is the
weight that these chemists carry into
every decision. And it's exactly why
building AI for scientific discovery has
taught us that above all else, trust is
actually the most important feature.
It's not accuracy in the abstract. It's
not right capability or amazing but
often isolated results.
But trust is when you have alignment
with their domain. This seems obvious
and I realize that and it's easy to lose
track of this though when you're
building capabilities without clear
problem selection criteria. Because when
your job as a chemist is to maintain a
material market segment that reaches a
billion people's hands, you have high
expectations. And the truth is that once
you reach a system and you begin to see
that it's beginning to reason in a
confidently wrong way, you don't just
lose trust in the answer. You begin to
lose trust in you, the one who's
actually developing the agentic system.
And winning either back is a very steep
climb. Now, the crazy thing is is that
trust doesn't break down through some
dramatic failure of complex reasoning.
It breaks down through something simple
and quiet. It's often times just basic
misalignment with their domain. This is
a simple example of that. This is a real
query from a formulation chemist
searching for an actual patent for the
agent to reason with. Two passages. Both
of them look like they could answer it.
One of them, however, is correct. And a
leading uh embedding model actually
ranks the correct answer in the 300th
position, well beyond actually the 300th
position, which is well outside what
typical reranking systems actually check
in production. And perhaps even more
surprising on this one was that the
difference in similarity score between
these two passages despite their
rankings with respect to the query was
actually almost the same. It was
basically a zero difference which means
that the model has absolutely no within
domain discrimination when it comes to
formulary chemistry. For an agentic
co-scientist, this isn't just a bad
retrieval at this point. It becomes a
false belief that it begins to reason
from very confidently. So to solve this
problem, what we have to do is we dig
under the surface and see what makes
these passages actually different. Both
passages share similar material
ontologies. They have similar function
and final application domain. But by
using an ontological signal to actually
surface what a formulation chemist would
use to tell these things apart, this is
how we actually begin to get domain
alignment and we can build powerful
training signals for within domain
discrimination.
Now for our customers and our partners,
this is a really important issue to be
able to find the right information. And
so we began to build benchmarks to
understand where within domain
discriminations like this live for
industrial chemistry. And using the same
public corpus across every model, we
find that commercial APIs score
effectively zero on this. They have no
within domain discrimination. Open-based
models do better, but even continued
pre-training on those doesn't actually
really work. What does work is when you
get to task specific ontologically uh
onlogically structured constructive
contrastive training um which teaches
the model the actual shape of the domain
chemistry. Not just showing it more
chemistry text, but actually finding
alignment with how the actual users
think. that took us from a near zero
model in production to something that
was actually meaningful at enterprise
scale. Um, we're finding that reasoning
and discovery where uncertainty can be
really high is only as good as the
alignment between the system and the
actual problem space that is applied to.
This is why we think that a lot of the
more scalable AI solutions are going to
have to be very AI uh sorry very domain
native which I think some of the talks
today we've seen that as we get to more
specialized domains um building AIs that
really understand that is good. The
example you just saw demonstrates trust
in the uh sorry how to restore trust in
the answer by aligning with the domain
but it's also focused on closing the gap
on public data. Longer term the more
important piece of trust is actually the
second kind which is the trust that you
have when building agentic systems for
actual users. um the public record of
science is survivorship biased and so as
a result you know we have a tendency to
um miss what's beneath the surface on a
lot of these things systems but a lot of
this knowledge does live inside of
enterprise R&D today and by focusing on
asking yourself the question of what are
we doing to actually build trust in the
AI that we're building for the end users
this is how you get access to this kind
of data thank you very much
[applause]
>> thank you Jonathan
Thank you, Jonathan. That was amazing.
Alrighty. So, next up, we have a session
by AMD. We're going to take about two
minutes just to set up the audio video
setup here so that they can present the
demo. We have a 10-minute talk by Mati
Goodsy and followed by a 60-minute demo
workshop presentation. So, please give
it up to Mati Goodsy and uh AV crew.
Come on up.
Okay.
>> Water.
This one has an HDMI. Oh, it does
like
Yeah, it's good. Yeah. All right. Hello
everybody. Uh my name is Maddie. Um here
from AMD. This talk that I'm going to
present right now is supposed to be our
uh vice president. Ramen prepared it but
he couldn't make it. So they asked me to
present it. So originally I was going to
just do the hands-on workshop that has
come in in about 10 minutes uh along
with my colleagues. Um but I will first
cover the presentation Ram prep prepared
and then we'll get to the hands-on
workshop. Just a couple notes about the
hands-on workshop that's coming up soon.
Um it will be basically on your own
device. So you have if you have your
laptop it' be great to connect to Wi-Fi
prepare. uh my colleagues going to pass
you guys that are in person a piece of
slip that will have a URL that you can
basically access that environment we
prepared for you guys. Uh I would ask
you to hold off on doing it and do it
right after the presentation but just be
prepared for it.
Okay. Um so the topic that we prepared
for you guys for this talk is about um
how the measure of work is changing and
we're going from tokens to outcome. Um
and before we all so obsessed with
tokens per second and now it's going to
cost per finished task. Uh this is going
to happen through our most recent work
with uh the latest model from Moonshot
AI. So Kim K3 where we basically worked
with them to make sure we have day zero
support. So we go through how this whole
thing is changing within the data center
and AMD.
All right. To to start with something
that sounds obvious and it's going to
turn a little bit expensive later is
when you think about um AI chat uh in
terms of how it works, it's basically a
bounded uh task. So you have a user
sends a prompt, you get the response to
the human, you read it and it's done.
But when it comes to agentic AI, uh it's
a bit different. It's not bounded
anymore. So you basically have that uh
same query going there, but the agent
plans, maybe does some tool calling, it
looks at the result, maybe doesn't like
it, you know, calls the tool again,
maybe starts a whole graph engineering
loop of agents to go through it. And now
the same sort of work could be seconds
or could be hours. Um
so how is this changing things for us?
Um it basically means at this point that
from outside view when you're planning
things for in terms of capacity or you
know how much of budget you allocate for
your uh team. Um it's a lot different
now because now before you basically go
for the seats and have uh you know users
assigned to the models or service but
now one user could take you know few
seconds to get response one user could
be ours and that's a whole new magnitude
of uh difference between the amount of
compute that's needed for each of those
tasks.
this way of uh the change that is
happening is going to break a few
things. So three of them that we
highlighted here are uh first budgeting
and I think this is one of the reasons
my VP put there because I believe in the
beginning of the year we were budgeting
for the whole year of compute for our
team and we blew through that within a
few weeks and this is happening across
the industry. So two people using the
same service one person could be 10 or
100 times more expensive given that task
you know may require hours of loop in
through into through agents.
Uh the second thing is before we're all
very obsessed with flops and tokens per
second and how GPU is fast enough to
handle those tasks. Now it's a bit
different. So the context is growing so
fast with the whole multi-turn agent
runs that it's now the whole system. And
now we need to optimize the system
differently because we there's a lot of
memory bound now.
And in terms of the scorecard again,
tokens per second was what we were
obsess obsessed with. But now it doesn't
tell you um much uh about you know how
how much computers needed is because
it's about the finished task. It's not
just about you know one response.
Okay.
Um so all of them I'm going to talk
about is about the same principle um
which is in short as caching
every turn repeats work from the last
turn that uh already did. So if you
think about the context in uh a loop of
uh agent you have you know on the 12th
run you basically need to still compute
all the 11th runs that you don't you've
done before and move on to the what are
little bit left on the 12th one
but the obvious answer is why don't we
redo the calculations that we already
done so we should keep it and this is
something that we've been discovered and
you know done for the past previous
years but now it's bit changed so the
whole way that we do this is across
three different uh silos. So we have it
done in the models, we have it done on
the GPU stack and also on the CPU. So
all these three in parallel are working
to make sure we don't hit that memory
band problem.
So let's let's get started with you know
a few quick examples of how this
happened with our moonshot AI
collaboration for Kim K3.
The first one is in the model point of
view. So the problem is that KV cache
grows rapidly. So every time you know
you get a new response it grows and
grows and grows. Um that could be very
large for very large models. It could
get to hundreds of gigabytes and you
can't keep all of that in your memory
especially HPM the fastest memory for
GPU.
So what they've done with Kimi K3 and
all the models that are basically in the
past few years they tried to optimize
that and the very interesting thing
about Kim K3 was they actually went out
of the 93 layers 69 of them are based on
this whole new concept of KDA which is
Kimmy uh delta attention which basically
it it uses uh linear attention with uh
recurrent layers. So actually you have a
fixed amount of tokens that being
computed for those layers. So in our
experiment on AMDMI 355 GPU which one
node has eight GPUs each of them 288 GB
it only um was about 15.5 GB of um
memory. So that's a lot smaller better
for us to uh compute.
Okay, next is
the GPU serving stack.
Um, you can't basically have a very uh
feasible uh data center when you have um
that cache for every request be saved in
HPM.
So with the new model uh from Moonshot,
we basically went through the whole
redesigningness of in terms of the
tiered um tiered um caching. So what we
have right now is a HPM under it you
have your um uh
basically it will be HPM then you have
your DM from the CPU and then SSD and
under that you have the the pool memory.
So all of these together basically
creates a tiers and the whole point is
when you have a agentic run uh the agent
basically runs a task it waits for the
the results to come back. So whether
it's a tool call or uh whatever it's
done on the CPU there's a lot of idle
time. So when the eviction happens you
want to make sure that GPU is still busy
and it's being used. So a lot of that
cash sometime gets evicted with a tiered
way of how we we've done it now. you
basically have it ready the basically
the uh prefix is ready for you when the
model is ready to run the task. So
that's how we went from typical on the
99th percentile where we used to get you
know uh with the previous method of se
17.3 seconds down to 5.4 that's 3.22 two
times faster than before.
[snorts]
On the CPU side, uh again with aentki,
the CPUs become a lot a lot more
relevant. We have a lot of compute
happening there and that's where we, you
know, we can talk about how the tools
can be called more efficiently, how the
CPU execution could be a lot more
efficient. And one good example is the
tokenization part of it. So you can also
cache that. And this is another example
that we're trying to show that uh if you
just basically cache what's new, you
kind of get a flat rate of 0.09
milliseconds compared to recomput the
whole thing that is 1.7 seconds. So we
also get a lot of um compute efficiency
on the CPU side.
And we wanted to also include this part
uh that basically might sound a bit
confusing for some people that you know
um how the numbers and the amount of
work that you calculate is changed. A
lot of people report the hit rate for
cash, but uh you can see here in this
example, you go you go actually a lower
uh cash hit rate. So you went from
88.5%.
To 87.5. So in you know when you look at
first you're like wow this is this is
worse. But the reality is we talked
about the time to first token previously
when it said 3 times better and actually
that's what we measure now. So it's
about the successful run because that
88.5%
um doesn't mean a lot if you still have
to compute the first token. So you have
to go a lot longer experience. So at the
end the user gets a better experience
with lower cash hit rate. So you still
have you know um better experience but
the whole problem is we need to report
cost and time per successful run not
just tokens per second and those
measures that we used to do before.
And this kind of concludes the the first
part of our presentation. So the winner
is whoever finishes the most tasks per
per dollar and things are changing for
AMD and uh it's moving forward to a
different direction and we're going to
see more of that. So thank you for this
part of it. We're going to quickly move
to the the workshop slide which I don't
know if you all got the piece of paper.
Did you
you all have it? Okay. So this part is
going to be a hands-on part. I'm going
to be doing it with Satia. Um this is um
I think a great experience because you
get to also see how you can run your
agents efficiently in a hybrid manner.
Might take us a minute to switch
laptops.
Can you tell them we have prizes so they
don't
also raise their hands?
You ready?
you guys.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. A couple things about this
part of the workshop. So, as I
mentioned, it's a hands-on workshop. The
last part of the workshop is for you
guys to finish a challenge. It's going
to be about 10 minutes of whatever you
guys can finish within that 10 minutes.
Uh we do have some AMD swags as a
giveaway for people who actually finish
the challenge and rank within the top,
you know, whatever number of prizes we
have. Um,
and I guess for people who are joining
online, um, due to capacity, we
prioritize the people that attend in
person, but I'm going to show be showing
a link that you guys can, uh, fill up
and then we'll email you compute to
follow this workshop later.
So along the same theme of what we I was
talking about so far is about efficiency
uh you know uh saving tokens and this
workshop is basically going to use um
open claw. How many of you guys have
ever used open claw by the way?
>> A few. All right. So you you're going to
be exposed to open claw but we're not
going to do a deep dive on openclaw.
It's more of how you can actually have
the agents u be able to uh decide on uh
model usage. So we're going to kind of
cover mixture of models. Um and this is
the theme of the workshop to save you
guys token in terms of cost and privacy
and efficiency.
Uh one thing to make sure we cover here
for all the developers um there is
content such as this that I'm going to
present today and free compute with free
AMD developer program. Uh you do get
bunch of benefits that listed there. I'm
not going to go through all of them, but
basically free courses, free GP credits,
free um uh giveaways that we will send
to the lucky winners every month.
This is a link for the people attending
virtually. Um as I mentioned, please go
into this link. You should be able to
see a new uh card added for you guys.
Request even credits. Uh if you fill
that form, we will be able to email you
with a unique uh link within the next
few days to be able to follow the same
workshop we're doing today. [snorts]
About us, um my name is Maddie. I just
introduced myself earlier. Satia is my
co-orker within the same team. And we
have in a lobster costume, but on the
slide right now. So, she's she's the one
that's going to support us on the side.
So, she's one of our TAs. We have a few
TAs here. If you if you run into any
problems during this workshop, please
put your hands up and we'll have one of
the TAs to come help you.
Um again the theme don't compute what
you don't need to and also focus on uh
privacy, security and efficiency.
Um a lot of a lot of what we're going to
talk about today is about routing right.
um by default when I bring up the
routing to a lot of people developers
the first thing they think about is u mo
routing inside the model and that's the
idea of a mixture of experts um just to
cover a little bit of background you
know um the whole idea of routing one of
the notable papers was from 1991 from
Jeff Henon and his team where they
actually explored this idea but that was
early days with compute was not as
strong as right now and the models were
a lot smaller
They came back to the same idea in 2017
and they basically explored it for a
much bigger model. They went I think um
to a model if I remember correctly over
one bit on uh trillion parameters um and
this discovered more throughout there
such as sparse gating and how they can
actually have a better uh expert uh
selection through that gating algorithms
they had
>> and this is continuous so you see more
and more coming and coming and it's more
of a state-of-the-art uh as of right now
but the same idea of routing could be
applied to models. So instead of having
the expert to be what you route to, you
can actually have the models to be the
endpoint. And today that's what we're
going to cover. We're going to basically
have a model that's running on a box
that is like just like this. It's in a
data center. Um might be a slightly
different form factor, but the same sort
of compute. So this is the AMD uh Ryzen
AI Halobox. It's available uh in the
market to purchase. Uh basically has um
a very strong CPU. So you can run runs
run model locally. We're going to show
that quickly uh in one of the slides,
but that's what I'm going to be using to
run the local model and you also have a
cloud model. The point for that is um
the three pillars that I've shown here.
Um you can actually save a lot of money
on the cost because not every token
deserves that best frontier model out
there.
>> If for example you're looking for a file
or looking for simple command, you don't
need to send that to your Fable 5. Thank
you.
>> Uh in terms of quality, um you can
escalate when it's needed and also have
some specialized model to handle those,
you know, tasks that you can uh get done
with a specialized model. And finally,
privacy and security. Um I have a lot of
personal files on my computer and I
don't feel comfortable sending that to
cloud. Um I don't want my social
security number to show up in somebody's
training data. So maybe that's a better
idea to keep it locally.
The idea that we're going to present
today about mixture of models is not our
idea. It's been something that you know
have been explored um in academia
in 2023. For example, there's a paper
frugal GPT that came out uh and they
showed how they can actually have uh a
one model that basically judges the the
response that goes to the small model.
If they're happy with the results, they
just keep it. Otherwise, they escalate
to the cloud model. So that's one idea
was explored and they showed they can
actually save 98% of total cost by doing
so and got very similar results to GPD4
at the time.
The idea was again explored a little bit
further. So they thought about you know
how how about to be basically have this
is a paper from Berkeley um you can have
route LLM which is have a router that
decides what model to use. Instead of
first using a model, you basically have
a router that can automatically decide
and it also showed very promising uh
results based on that and saving over uh
two times of cost.
And then there's semantic routing. So
today we're going to be covering a
version of semantic routing through AMD
born project is called Lemonade and they
have that baked into their uh system and
it runs on local systems such as this
one. Uh the idea is very simple. Um you
basically have an embedder that embeds
that request that comes in there and it
tries to uh classify based on that you
know vector that it produces whether
this is a better fit for model A or B
based on the rules you defined and it
uses you know similarity such as coine
similarity to figure out what that that
model is going to be.
A very quick little intro on openclaw.
OpenCloud is a much bigger project, but
if you've never heard of it, it
basically got super popular earlier this
year. It is known as the most popular
open source software out there right
now. Um, it's basically your agentic
runtime. I believe the founder is also
in this conference. We can meet him
later. Um, but OpenClaw
for what we do today is we're using that
very simple agent creation and we
created a few agents for you guys to
play with. uh you're going to see that
momentarily how you can actually um have
those routing techniques that I talked
about exercised through open cloud. The
quick thing I want you guys to know that
every agent you create has its own
workspace. Those workspace have bunch of
MD files as configuration files that you
can use. So MD for example is one of
them. Agents MDs. Another one
opencloud.json JSON is that all
configuration for the models, which
models you use and what permissions you
have. Um, and we're going to be creating
well, we already created them for you.
For example, the local brain agent that
you're going to use is connected to a
local model. The cloud one is going to
be a cloud Kim model that's running on a
cloud. And a smart router is going to be
how we can actually create a router
ourselves today in a workshop.
Um so we're going to cover four
different kinds of routing. The first
one is I think anybody who's using cloud
code or any sort of coding agents you
probably know that you can just do slash
model and change. That's the simplest
one but be progressively get a little
bit more difficult. Um how you can have
a dedicated agent for each model or you
can have automatic routing. So you know
one agent decides if that task needs to
be escalated to the bigger model based
on the rules you define and then
semantic routing which I covered
briefly. So we have that in Lemonade and
Satia is going to cover that.
Okay.
The setup for the workshop is going to
look like this. Uh you have a virtual
environment. U so if you have that piece
of paper in front of you, it's good time
to maybe log in right now and make sure
you're logged in and can access that. Um
there is going to be AMD Ryzen AMX 395
plus uh for running that local model
using Lemonate and then anytime you need
to escalate to a more uh frontier model
we using Fireworks AI which is running
this model with AMD MI355 GPUs and it's
served uh on the cloud
the CPU and the system and the one
you're going to be using a little bit
more about it I think just want to
highlight the in terms of the unified
memory it has iGPU as a CPU and as MPU
So together they can actually run models
pretty efficiently for you guys. Uh 128
gigabyte of uh unified memory means that
you can run models up to 200 billion
parameters at a lower precision and fork
and be able to serve your models
locally.
This is a box that I'm showing. This is
a small for form factor of this uh that
you guys can purchase and use as your
always running agent host.
Lemonade. We have one of the founders of
Lemonade actually sitting on the site.
Uh if you want to have a chat with them,
Krishna. Um this is again something that
was burned in AMD to be able to have a a
way of running models locally very fast.
So you can basically just download with
a desktop app and you're good to go with
downloading models and running them on
AMD hardware.
More about Lemonade. I encourage you
guys to maybe scan the the QR code, take
a photo if you want to get engaged in
the community.
and we should get directly to our
workshop. Um, maybe switch and then we
can display this on the on the side.
>> Awesome.
>> Can I actually see show hands? How many
of you guys are actually connected to
the instance and you have it up? That's
great. All right. Quite a few of you
guys. That's great.
>> Okay.
So, it's going to look like very similar
to what I have here, right? Um,
so you basically should have a little
site notes for you guys. That's cover
and story. So, we're going to go through
the story. So, first is maybe you click
on the story side on the right side.
[snorts]
And then you should be able to see all
the instructions that we're going to
follow today. Um just very very few
beginning points that I need to mention
here
are uh we're gonna be switching between
the terminal and a browser. If you never
touch the terminal, don't worry, you can
still finish this. You literally just
there's buttons that you paste commands
in there. Okay.
>> And if you do need to have access, you
maybe came late or you still need it,
please put your hands up. Ida uh can can
help you.
>> Okay. Uh and if you ever fall behind,
we've made it very clear. You can just
basically follow the story, but I'm
going to be going through this with
Satia. We can follow along. So first, uh
in terms of terminal access, um we have
instructions here. But anytime we say go
to terminal, um you basically need to
have only a few open. Don't open every
time a new terminal. Just keep the ones
that you have open already and switch
between them. Um when I say new terminal
tab, so first of all, terminal you can
open from application, right?
application terminal emulator. That
would open this terminal. If you say
open a new terminal tab, that that's
when you actually have this little plus
button here. You can uh press that and
it will open new tab.
>> And throughout the workshop, we have
these bands to make it super clear for
you guys so you don't get lost that you
know this is this next prompt. You're
going to be switching to browser or you
switch to terminal or open a new
terminal tab. Start a new open clause
session. You're going to see how we're
doing that. It's basically going to be
in the terminal. Um, and we just type
openclaw space tui and that should open
it.
Um, and then inside openclaw tui, you
already have your agent there for you to
be able to talk to. And that that would
be basically what it is. One thing you
should probably avoid doing though so is
copy pasting. This is a an emulated
machine. So you can't just like use your
mouse to copy paste. So avoid doing
that. It's not going to work. That's why
we have these buttons. So the very first
thing you want to do is just have one
little hello world with the with the
agent. Make sure everything is working
and then we move on from there. Uh that
is introduction. So we're going to do
open cloud tui session uh workshop. If
you just literally have the cursor um
like the one I have and just paste
command. Anytime you press paste
command, it pastes where the cursor is.
So if I just do this, you should be able
to see that pastes in terminal and you
should be able to access your openclaw
um environment.
It's great. It's up. Uh, basically
saying hi. Let's say hi. Make sure it's
working. Hi.
My name is Maddie.
[snorts]
Great. Uh, so a few points here
throughout the workshop. If I say like
you're on this agent and you kind of got
lost, you could see the agent is main.
We have a few agent agents set up for
you guys. you're going through them
quickly, but as of right now, this agent
main to to switch between agents, you
still like if you follow, you don't need
to do it. But in case if you get lost,
if you just do slash agent and [snorts]
press enter, you should be able to
select. Okay. Um,
and just like follow along. If I say,
you know, on main agents, make sure
you're on the main or switch between
them.
seats. Just ask them to refresh
in earlier.
>> Oh, um I just was notified that some
people maybe couldn't log in earlier.
There's more allocations now. If you
couldn't connect to this environment,
just refresh your page uh and it should
be able to connect.
Okay. Uh the very first way of routing,
I mentioned that we're not going to
spend much time on it. any agent you
have. If you actually have bunch of
models in the in the open cloud JSON
added there, all you have to do is
slashmodel
or just paste this command that I have
here. Press enter and you should be able
to see all the models that we have ready
for you guys. You can switch between
them, right? For now, we're going to
start with the fireworks model from, you
know, commun 2.6 on fireworks. Enter.
That should be it. Okay. Um, I already
did my hello. I'm one step ahead, but if
you're not, make sure you introduce
yourself before we move on to the next
part.
Okay. Uh now we're on page two. There's
going to be five pages here. Page two.
Um we're going to switch to a browser to
start that Lemonate server uh that we
have for you guys um to be able to track
any sort of u you know uh server logs.
So basically if you have the browser
open you should be able to just
basically copy this thing here. So
localhost 13305 or just paste URL press
enter it should come up [snorts]
and then we're going to switch back to
the terminal. So you should be able to
see up here that I actually have the
terminal. Um these are the tabs I have
open. So, if I go on the terminal
and I open a new tab,
as it says here, open a new terminal
tab. Just open new tab and we're going
to paste this command. So, what this
command is doing is basically tracking
your last little prompt to see if it's
running on the cloud or what model and
what kind of like approximate cost could
be. Uh, so we've done this for you guys
to be able to kind of like switch back
and forth between terminals if you're
interested to see like, you know, what
model you're using, how it's routed, and
what the cost is. Plus, on the very end,
the challenge, you'll be relying on this
to report how much you spent on your
tokens. Okay, going back to your open
cloud UI session, I believe, let me make
sure I'm following right. Okay, first
act number one, that's where we are.
Local versus cloudbrain.
Um,
this is a scenario that I want you guys
to think about. Like first of all um
what so I showed you guys that we we do
you know slash model to switch between
models but there might be reasons that
you want to actually have a dedicated
agent so I'd say like I want to have one
agent to always be running my local
model and one agent to be always be um
you know cloud can someone say like one
of the reasons why I want to do that
like why would I even want to like have
that dedicated agent
>> data
>> personal data That's correct. And the
reason that maybe you couldn't have the
reason that you know that main agent
wouldn't work to expand on what you said
is you can actually set rules for each
agent. So right now I want to set the
rule for this agent that don't ever
touch my u you know personal files if
you're cloud cloud agent. So I want to
disable that. If you use one big agent
you can't go set rules like this. It's
going to be a lot more difficult. So one
of the reason you want to have this you
know uh local versus cloud agent to
separate the agents completely is that
you can set the rules. you can set u
permissions and also create the context
that is more suitable for that model.
So here uh to do so it says open a new
terminal tab. We're going to do that
[snorts]
and you're going to paste this command.
So all it's doing is basically going
through the list of agents I have. It
finds that uh cloud agent and make sure
that I dis disabled the the permissions
to access the local files.
Next, you need to restart your OpenCloud
to make sure this is picked up because
we changed this JSON config file. So
again on the same terminal that I was, I
just paste this command which is
OpenCloud gateway restart. Press enter
and you should be able to uh get
messages similar to one what I have that
G gateway is restarted and it's ready to
use. There we go.
And I'm going to go back to my first
terminal which I had open cloud TUI. So
this is start a new open claw session.
You can either do a new tab or just go
back to the first one I had. Uh control
ctrl C c should kill it. And if you just
go up or just type this uh you know open
code session workshop uh same thing
it'll bring up the TUI. [snorts]
Okay. Here I want you guys to switch to
um actually you are already on the cloud
brain. So if if you are not on the cloud
uh brain, you should do uh agent
and then go cloud brain
or just paste that command uh in your
open cloud TUI. So you should be able to
see something like this that says agent
cloud brain
here. What here's the agent that we just
disabled it from running the files. So
let me just reset my context from last
run that they had here.
Okay. So, basically here I have um a
prompt ready for you guys. I have a file
on the system. I want to make sure that
it it works. It doesn't access that
file. So, if I just press enter and it
says read the content of this financial
CSV file. Since we disabled the the
services, it shouldn't be able to access
that. And you can see that u you know it
it gives me hey I don't have access to
local file system and therefore I can't
do it. to switch to your local brain. Uh
that that is another agent we have that
is dedicated to that local model. Very
similar concept. I can maybe skip this
for the sake of time, but if you just do
slash agent local brain and type the
exact same command, then you should see
that financial report is actually
printed and it it works fine. So this is
just to show you guys how you can have
two different agents. One of them with
set permissions to not be able to access
your local file and one of them does.
Okay, I'm gonna skip 1B. As I mentioned,
it's the basically the same thing, but
you get the idea. So, we're going to go
to uh page number three.
That's act two. This is where we're
going to start doing a little bit more
automatic way. So far, you were the
router. So, you were the one that
picking which model to pick based on
your need. Now in open cloud there is a
way that you can actually set it up in a
way that you always route to one model
and you actually ask that model to tell
you if this should be escalated to the
cloud model and that's what we're going
to do next. So to do so um if you
remember I mentioned that openclaw has
um you know those uh config files. So
switching back quickly to um this slide
just make sure we're following.
So we just did this part which basically
you have a cloud brain and that has its
own config files and local brain and you
know you can set permissions. Next what
we're going to do is create a smart
router way of doing things and we
created the agent for you guys. So what
we going to do is basically add bunch of
rules in that uh main agent um soul.md
file that basically tells that for these
rules I want you to escalate to the
cloud model or for these rules just use
local and that's as simple as that
going back to my workshop tab. So if you
just switch uh oh actually before that I
want to show you quickly what the rules
are. So we're going to do one more new
tab. So I basically have four four tabs
total. And if I just paste agent uh
agent smart router. Oh sorry not the
first one I'm going to do uh the genome
text editor. This is the one that we
doing right now. Open new terminal tab.
So genome text editor. We paste this.
Press enter. It should open that soul MD
for the smart router agent. So very
briefly
every time I'm going to ask this agent
to work um it's going to do this. Every
single response must be begin with
exactly one of these two lines. It's
either cloud or or the local. So the
classification should follow with some
rules. Um the rules I have for it is for
example if I'm asking you to write a
code use cloud. If I ask you to read a
file use local. So these rules are going
to be followed by this agent
automatically. So I don't need to every
time select what model I want to choose
or what agent want to choose. And you
can have a more automatic way of doing
so. Okay. Uh we don't need this is just
for information to see where we changed
this where we had it. The last thing is
um just the point is the way it's going
to work if it's going to escalate to the
cloud model is actually going to create
a sub agent and that sub agent is going
to have that uh cloud model and that's
all configured through this uh solar MD
file.
Let's close these. Go back to our
terminal. And I believe this is where we
switch to the smart router agent. So if
you go here slash slash agent
go to smart router
and it should be open for you guys to to
use. Um we're going to do two simple
prompts and then we're going to move to
Satio's part which is the semantic
routing part of things. So first prompt
I want to show you guys is something
that we should see it's happening local
but you should be able to see how that
happens. So what does a four-year
vesting schedule with a one-year cliff
mean? Because in the in the rules, I
don't have that set uh in to go to cloud
and the local model should be able to
handle. You could see that the very
first thing we get from here is
classification. This is a local model
and therefore it's going to basically go
and um use the local model to respond to
it.
This will take a few seconds as if it's
uh going through all the full uh thing.
But
yeah, so here we go. classification
local. Uh it's a straightforward fial
question. So I'm just going to use my
local model and therefore I got this.
The very last part for me before I move
on is just to show you guys another
prompt that based on the rules that's
following what we ask. Uh so we ask it
to if you ever ask to write a code it
should escalate to uh you know the cloud
model and that's what's happening next.
So if I say write a python function to
calculate loan interest payments and
press enter
since this is writing code you should
see the very first thing it says is
classification cloud so it's going to
direct to that fireworks model and um
behind the scenes how openclaw works is
they're going to create a little small
agent pass it all the context say
session spawn go do this then it waits
for the agent to come back and once it's
come back you get the results Um this is
going to take you know a few seconds to
to complete. If you don't get it you can
always just uh this is one thing that I
you know with open claw and agents you
can always boole it. If like if it
doesn't do something or you want you can
actually like ask us like hey what
happened to the results or what did you
do this or change your config. So here
if you don't get the results within like
a minute or two you can just always like
go like hey what was the final result.
Um well it's time for me to pass to
Satia because he's going to cover more
of uh Lemonade and he's in that team
that also worked on Lemonade and they
have that semantic routing baked into
it. So I'm going to ask Sio to continue
this workshop.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks Mari. Hey everyone. Uh so far we
have seen how to hardcode uh open claw
configuration files you know to help us
with our routing. But in this section,
we're going to see a more uh automated
setup through uh lemonade router. So
before we start the hands-on part, just
a quick uh graphic on like what the
system architecture how the how this
section basically works. So what we have
here is a a simple setup where you send
a prompt to open claw and it first goes
to lemonade router running locally and
uh the lemonade router decides where to
send your prompt. So if it's a sensitive
question, it goes to a local small
model. Or if it's a complex question, it
goes to a cloud model like Kimik2.6.
Or if it's a complex question that
doesn't that doesn't sorry that has uh
sensitive information, it goes to a
local slightly larger model like Quen
3.635B.
Now uh moving on to the hands-on part.
So in in this in this setup we have
defined some skills. So these skills are
nothing but where you point your data
sources, output expectations and uh you
know input guidelines like how the skill
uh has to work. These are basically
we're instructing open claw on how to uh
handle the data or the question. So in
this section uh you guys are managing a
startup uh where you have uh where your
role is to uh handle employees on
boarding, leaving uh answering questions
on you know benefits data, finance
questions, legal questions etc. And
we're going to uh do this using a set of
skills.
The skills are defined inside open
clause skills folder like uh these are
all you know preconfigured. Uh if I just
open one of them, it's just a simple uh
guide you know for open claw that this
is where you get your data source.
You're authorized to do certain tasks.
You shouldn't do certain tasks. So
that's that's just a quick summary on
skills. Now
go to a new uh terminal and then let's
start a new uh open clotti session for
this for this part and the first agent
is uh HR admin agent. Uh let me reset my
instance. Yeah. So we have employees CSV
datas. Basically it has a bunch of uh
PII sensitive information personally
identifiable information like SSN email
phone number etc. Now uh we're going to
switch to fireworks uh our cloud model
and then ask a simple onboarding
question. So as you can see this is
where I'm tagging the skill the HR
admin. If I go back to my skills folder
this is where the skill.md file sits and
uh I want to ask my uh cloud model to
onboard an employee. So to look at the
data, this is this is where we have all
the data. Uh this is the employees CSV
where the cloud model is currently
writing to. So if I open it,
as you can see uh the the Jordan Lee
employee got onboarded. But what's the
catch here? we just like exposed a bunch
of uh sensitive information to a cloud
model. Right? Now the alternative here
is to use uh a local model. But how can
we automate this? We we we don't want to
switch uh for every question right
between a cloud and local model. So in
order to do that uh we'll be using the
lemonade router. So I'll be selecting
the HR admin router uh from the
drop-down. You do /model and then select
the user.hrmin router. Now I'm going to
ask a similar question. Uh this time
onboarding a different employee Maya. Uh
let's see. Uh
so if I go back to the lemonade uh
dashboard, you can find it at 1305. And
as you can see the local model got
loaded. But the reasoning behind this is
you can expand lemonade router and then
click on the gear icon next to HR admin
router. And this is where you have the
basic uh LLM based routing. So you uh
you select your candidate models. In my
case, I've selected a cloud model and a
small local model Quen 3.69B.
And then my national language and my uh
router LLM is again quen 3.59B
which decides uh where to route this
question. So the routing prompt is like
very simple. If you see any personally
identifiable information uh send it to a
local model. Uh for anything else just
uh send it to a fireworks model, right?
Uh now going back to my TUI. Yeah, as
you can see.
Yeah, I think got it on boarded.
It's found some inconsistencies in the
question.
Okay.
Oh, okay. Uh, I forgot to change the
date. But, uh, you get the idea like it
is supposed to go and uh, write the
data. If you if I change it to
first.
Okay.
uh yeah so in this case we have like
zero data leaving our machine and uh all
the data is staying local
along with you know the routing. Now
while that is running uh you can see the
lemonade logs running in the back end
where you can see uh the TTFT TPS and
other metrics for this local model.
Now uh for the second part.
Yeah, looks like it is done.
Close this.
Yeah. So it got onboarded the new
employee and this is done using a local
model without any data leaving the
machine. Now moving on to the second
agent, our benefits agent. Uh this is a
simple the agent's goal is to perform uh
rag on a set of data sets. Uh in this
case benefits handbook.mmarkdown.
Now let's uh directly switch to the
lemonade router instead of going to a
cloud. I'm going to select user.benefits
router
and then ask a simple rack question.
So if I go to the router and then expand
the benefits router. So this is where
you define your keywords, regular
expressions
and uh you know uh whether your input
has images or if there is any tool
calling. So these are the set of rules
that I've defined for this uh for this
agent. And this question has no uh the
question basically is asking when does
my 401k vesting cliff happens. So this
goes to a simple benefits rag rule. And
if you click on expand in advanced the
same quick rules gets expanded to the
advanced rule section. And if I go to
the simple benefits rack I I have the
keywords defined here. So if you see any
question on 401k or vesting or if the
question is like and if the question is
below 400 characters route it to a local
model. So that's what happened just now
and the question got routed to a local
model and uh we also have like some a
bunch of other rules for uh PII and
complex queries. I'm going to cover them
later. As you can see, we got the
response from the local model and uh we
we didn't uh we didn't spend any uh
dollars on a cloud model for this simple
question. Right now, um I'm going to ask
a slightly complex question. Again, a
local model can handle it, but I want to
show the difference between uh the
routing scenarios. So, now this time
it's a it comes under uh complex benefit
analysis. As you can see, if I'm asking
questions about comparison uh an
analysis, data analysis, etc. or you
know any benchmarking related questions
or if the prompt is longer than uh 800
characters, send it to the fireworks
Kimmy K2.6 model. So now uh yeah, the
fireworks model has answered the
question for us and we didn't have to
switch between different models, right?
The router took care of all of that
routing. And moving on to the third
agent, uh the finance agent. So again,
uh we this the agent's goal is to
perform data analysis over uh CSV files.
The uh these are like a bunch of uh
example uh CSV files with dummy data.
Now moving on, let me select the finance
router and then ask a simple question
about the burn rate like you know what
is our current burn rate. Now if I go to
the finance router.
So this is this should open the advanced
rule section and uh we have defined uh
different uh finance related topics here
and uh we have a semantic similarity uh
type selected and we also have like
classifier LLM based uh routing. So we
are using a simple embedding model. Uh
what it does is it uh performs a cosign
similarity between the concepts that we
defined here and the input prompt and
then uh it gives us a score of 0 to one.
And in our case the what is our current
burn rate maps with simple lookup. And
if I go to my
simple metric lookup here, here we I
defined my I defined my label here out
of all the three labels available and if
the threshold is greater than 0.6, route
it to a local model. Right?
So yeah, so we have our uh local model
answering this question.
Now moving on to a slightly complex
question where you know we're asking
about uh multissource analysis. So this
time it goes to deep modeling
and
yeah
so if I go back to my finance topic deep
modeling concept and uh this is where
like I define some examples. I I I
didn't put the exact question here but a
bunch of questions that kind of
summarizes my input question and I also
defined another uh label this time an
LLM doing uh my routing or
classification between if it's a complex
question or a simple question. So I've
asked an LLM like quen 3.59B to classify
my question between complex and simple
and uh if it says so if either of these
two rules gets kicked in that's when the
uh local the cloud model fires. So in
this case if the complexity label gets
more than 0.5 uh threshold uh or label
then it goes to cloud model
or if it's uh if it's a semantic uh if
the semantic uh model emitting model
gives rating more than 0.72
uh it goes to a in this case as you can
see deep modeling it goes to a cloud
model. So now uh this question got
answered by a cloud model.
Yeah. So that's it on our end. We have a
challenge
for you guys and the QR code should take
you to a form. We have some gifts. So if
you can solve this uh task, I think I
don't know how long we have. There may
be 10 minutes or so. Just uh let us
know. uh we have like we're tracking
these scores and you're supposed to use
the lowest amount of tokens possible to
solve this task. You can use a local
model or you can use a cloud model. You
can also use uh lemonade router or just
use plain routing up to you. And these
are the gifts.
Okay, we'll just let them do it.
If you can take a picture of this, I'll
have the leaderboard open.
It's lunch time.
>> It's up to you.
>> I'm fine with
It's okay if you want to
go for lunch.
>> Yeah, I think we're at time uh for
lunch. So, we have a booth there uh AMD
booth. Uh please drop by if you're done
with the challenge and uh we can
distribute the gifts there. Thank you.
the QR
Good job.
Did everyone get a picture of the QR
code? The challenge. All good.
Thank you.
All righty. Thank you everyone. For
everyone still here, we're going to
start the sessions again at 1:30. Um,
right now we have a break for lunch,
which uh goes until 1:30. So, lunch is
going to be where you checked in. That
area is going to be where lunch is
served.